What we want to talk about now is setting up the block for a return.
We have a couple of linemen here to show a couple of different things we can do with a return.
First of all, it starts with the stance (video demo).
These guys will get in a good three point stance to be ready to go across the line.
There are a couple of things we can do.
One, we can have these guys rush the kicker.
If we know that they have a bad snapper or a slow kicker we might try to get there and block the kick.
If we have that on we're not so worried about our return as we are getting in there to block the kick.
If we do that, you can see that their inside arms, which are the inside arms to the ball, they will be able to rip through with those, explode out and they're going to go get the ball.
If it's that situation, it will look like this (video demo).
They'll be going all out to try to get to the kicker.
Now we'll be blocking a little different because we're going to be blocking for the return.
If we're going to block for the return we want this guy to get a good punch on me and then we want him to sprint back and turn and find the blockers and set up for the return.
It will look something like this (video demo).
They'll sprint back, they'll turn around and find their defender and then come up and make the block.
The most important thing is to get a good hit at the beginning and then sprint back where their return man is, turn around and go find your blockers and help him out as much as possible.
That's how you set up the block for the return.